bp.com 2017-06-25

# Privacy statement | BP Global

### Information about our organization and website

BP p.l.c. is responsible for this website, which is governed by the laws of England and Wales. The courts of England and Wales shall have exclusive jurisdiction over any dispute arising out of your use of it. BP p.l.c. is registered in the UK: 102498. 1 St James’s Square, London SW1Y 4PD. BP p.l.c. is registered with The Information Commissioner in the United Kingdom and the notification/registration number is Z8357852.

BP Group companies may carry out due diligence checks on potential and existing counterparties. These checks may involve BP collecting personal information via publicly available databases and other on/off-line sources. For information on how BP does this in accordance with applicable data privacy laws please contact [privacy3@bp.com](mailto:privacy3@bp.com).

### Collection, use and retention of personal information

This privacy statement, together with any other documents, policies, notices or other statements referred to herein sets out the basis on which we process personal information about you. Personal data is information that can identify a specific individual such as name, physical and/or email address and telephone number. If during your visit to this website you order products or services, enter a competition or promotion or otherwise submit information to us e.g., by filling in forms or responding to surveys, you are choosing to provide us with your personal information. You agree that it will be used to provide the information, products or services you request (including information on additional products and/or services which BP reasonably thinks may be of interest to you), and to help us understand how visitors use this website, in order that we can improve the visitor experience on this site.

Where you have subscribed to receive our newsletter(s), we are able to ensure you receive further related and informative communications by following your interactions with that communication, such as whether you receive, open or click on a link within an email communication. We offer you the option to unsubscribe in all our further communications.

For more information see the “Direct marketing” section below. Further, you may choose to provide personal information via our website to a third party - for more information on whose privacy statement applies see the “Hyperlinks and embedded functionality” section below.

Personal information is held by us from the date of collection for the purposes of providing you with the requested products or services, after which time it may be deleted or aggregated so that it no longer directly identifies you.

### Keeping personal information accurate and access

We are committed to ensuring that your personal information is kept accurate and up to date. However, we can only make changes to your personal information if you notify us. It is your responsibility to let us know if there are inaccuracies or changes to your personal information. Please notify us at [www.bp.com/contact](http://www.bp.com/en/global/corporate/general-enquiries.html "Opens in new window") if there are any changes to or inaccuracies in your personal information, providing us with sufficient information to enable us to identify you, so that any changes can be made.

In accordance with our internal policies you may ask us to provide you with access to any personal data we process about you. If you want access to your personal information contact [www.bp.com/contact](http://www.bp.com/en/global/corporate/general-enquiries.html "Opens in new window"). We may be able to charge you for providing such access.

### Security

Transmission of information via the internet is not always secure. We cannot guarantee the security of your data while being transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. However, once we have received your information, we take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorised access, improper use or disclosure, unauthorised modification or unlawful destruction or accidental loss of personal information once it is under our control. 

### Disclosures and transfers of personal information

Subject to the “Hyperlinks and embedded functionality” section below, BP does not sell or otherwise release your personal information to third parties to allow them to direct market their products and services to you. In order to provide our products and services we may, however, need to share your personal information with other companies within the BP Group, and/or third-party service providers that process data on our behalf. If you submit personal information to BP, you agree to such disclosure.  

Since BP operates globally, BP may want to transfer your personal information to other countries, including countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA). However, while in our control, we always seek to ensure that your personal information receives the same level of protection as it would had it stayed within the EEA, including seeking to ensure that it is kept secure and used only in accordance with our instructions and for the agreed purpose(s).

We reserve the right to disclose your personal information as required by law, or when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, request from a regulator or any other legal process served on BP. In the event that BP is subject to a takeover, divestment or acquisition we may disclose your personal information to the new owner of the business.

### Direct marketing

You agree that BP may send you marketing communications in line with your previously expressed marketing preferences. If you no longer wish to receive such, please contact us at [www.bp.com/contact](http://www.bp.com/en/global/corporate/general-enquiries.html "Opens in new window") to modify your preferences, or follow the opt-out instructions contained in each marketing communication.

### Site traffic information and cookies

Where your selected browser setting permits, when you visit this site and other BP sites, persistent cookies (and their functional equivalents, such as web beacons) are placed onto your computer. These log data about your visit to BP's websites based on your device's IP address.

For further information about cookies, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

This website uses persistent cookies, which:

  1. collect information about how visitors use it, allowing us to enhance the performance of our websites by analyzing such information (e.g., to maintain a consistent look and feel for the visitor) and
  2. increase the website’s functionality and make it more personal to you by allowing us to remember your previous choices (e.g., your location and preferred font type and size) and to provide any enhanced features detailed in the cookie-specific user notice.

These cookies expire two years after your last visit. The information they collect is not used to send you targeted advertising, identify who you are or remember where you’ve been on the internet (with the exception of logging visits to other BP sites). You agree that your attention was drawn specifically to this section of our privacy statement and to any explicit privacy notice given to you and that you consent to our use of these cookies for these purposes.

To delete or stop cookies being placed on your computer, refer to the help menu on your internet browser. In a few cases, blocking cookies may reduce the functionality of some websites or prevent access to them altogether.

### Questions about your personal information

If you have any questions relating to this privacy statement or the personal information we hold about you please contact us at [www.bp.com/contact](http://www.bp.com/en/global/corporate/general-enquiries.html "Opens in new window") or by post at the following address: BP.com team, 1 St James's Square, London SW1Y 4PD.

### Freedom of information enquiries

If you represent a public authority governed by the Freedom of Information Act and you wish to consult with a BP stakeholder about a potential disclosure of BP information pursuant to a request you have received please email [privacy3@bp.com](mailto:privacy3@bp.com) giving your name, the name of the public authority you represent, your contact details, the nature of the request and the deadline for disclosure and a responsible BP person will contact you.

### Children

BP does not knowingly collect information from children.

### Changes to this privacy statement

We review this privacy statement regularly and may modify it from time to time. We will place any updates on this webpage. By continuing to use this website after such changes have been made, you acknowledge and agree you have read, understood and accept the changes. This privacy statement was last updated on 28 November 2016.

### Hyperlinks and embedded functionality

Our website may contain links to content or other functionality provided by third parties which are outside our control and are not covered by our privacy statement, including the embedded search box facility. The search box on this website (“Search Box”) is powered by Google Inc (“Google”). You acknowledge and agree that Google’s privacy policy (located at <http://www.google.com/privacy.html>) shall apply to your use of the Search Box and by using the Search Box you consent to Google using your personal data in accordance with its privacy policy. Similarly, if you access other websites using links or use other embedded functionality provided by third parties, the operators of those websites may collect information from or about you which will be used by them in accordance with their privacy statement, which may differ from ours. We encourage you to read those providers’ privacy statements on their websites. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.

### BP data privacy rules

In addition to the commitments set out in this privacy statement, BP has created a set of data privacy rules, which apply to the processing of all personal information by BP. These privacy rules can be found here.

For any queries regarding this document please contact [privacy3@bp.com](mailto:privacy3@bp.com).

### Changes to the privacy statement

We review this privacy statement regularly and may modify it from time to time. We will place any updates on this webpage. By continuing to use this website after such changes have been made, you acknowledge and agree that you have read, understood and accept the changes. This privacy statement was last updated on 28 November 2016.
